Guide to the Lane Cooper papers, 1881-1959.
Cooper, Lane papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Lane Cooper papers, 1881-1959.
14-12-680
Lane, Cooper 1875-1959.
9.1 cubic ft.
Correspondence, Manuscripts, Printed Materials
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Personal and professional correspondence, manuscripts, notes, reviews, printed material, and other items.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor of English language and literature, Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Personal and professional correspondence, manuscripts, notes, reviews, printed material, and other items.
Includes correspondence with his father, Jacob Cooper of Rutgers University, and his mother; letters from students, academic colleagues, and others discussing problems encountered in teaching and study, literary matters, Cooper's and others' published works, the activities of the Concordance Society, and related topics. Correspondents include Albert S. Cook, Drury Cooper, Will Cooper, Mary L. Cooper, Charles G. Osgood, Harry Caplan, Marjorie Barstow Greenbie, Caroline Whipple Phillips, and many others. Also, manuscripts and notes for Cooper's publications; draft reviews; students' papers; correspondence and notes regarding Cooper's LOUIS AGASSIZ AS A TEACHER (1917); autobiographical notes; a notebook of quotations and comments; Cooper family genealogy and photographs; and printed material. Also, letters to Ralph A. Liddle, and material pertaining to the Lane Cooper Scholarship Fund.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cooper, Lane,1875-1959.; Agassiz, Louis, 1807-1873.; Caplan, Harry, 1896-1980.; Cook, Albert S.; Cooper family.; Cooper, Drury.; Cooper, Jacob, 1830-1904.; Cooper, Mary L.; Cooper, Will.; Greenbie, Marjorie Latta Barstow, 1891-; Liddle, Ralph A.; Osgood, Charles Grosvenor, 1871-1964.; Phillips, Caroline Whipple.; Concordance Society.; Cornell University--Faculty.; Cornell University.English Dept.; Cornell University.Lane Cooper Scholarship Fund.
Subjects:
English language--Study and teaching.; English literature--Study and teaching.; College teachers.
Form and Genre Terms:
Genealogies.; Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Correspondence
Series II. Assorted Files
CONTAINER LIST
- Correspondence, 1881-1959
  - Letters, Bodo de Beck, 1903-1959 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letters, Drury Cooper, 1901-1915 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Letters, Drury Cooper, 1916-1931 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Letters, Drury Cooper and others, 1933-1957 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letters re genealogy, telegrams, Lane Cooper's will, letters from Ella Rutledge to M. F. Boynton (re account of L. C. for New York community Trust), letter about Jacob Cooper, Yale, 1950-1952 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Letters, Carrie Coulter, 1904-1927 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Letters, Elizabeth Coulter Stephenson, 1904-1920 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Letters, Elizabeth Coulter Stephenson, 1922-1938 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Letters, Ephraim Cutter, 1907-1917 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Letters, Will Cooper (1896-1940), 1896-1905 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Letters, Will Cooper, 1906-1915 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Letters, Will Cooper, 1916-1922 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Letters, Will Cooper, 1923-1930 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Letters, Will Cooper, Delia G. Cooper and Mary Linn McDonnell, Wm. McDonnell, 1931-1940, Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Irish Cousins, Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Letters, Dr. L. C. Lane, 1896-1902 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Letters, Esther Cooper Poueck and children, 1931-1959 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Writings of Will Cooper and others, Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Letters, Albert S. Cook, 1897-1907 (Box 3a, Folder 1)
  - Letters, Albert S. Cook, 1908-1909 (Box 3a, Folder 2)
  - Letters, Albert S. Cook, 1910-1914 (Box 3a, Folder 3)
  - Letters, Albert S. Cook, 1915-1918 (Box 3a, Folder 4)
  - Letters, Albert S. Cook, 1919-1921 (Box 3a, Folder 5)
  - Letters, Albert S. Cook, 1922-1924 (Box 3b, Folder 1)
  - Letters, Albert S. Cook, 1925-02-17-1927-07-27 (Box 3b, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous papers relating to Albert Cook's death and related items, Undated (Box 3b, Folder 3)
  - Letters, Cook Family Emily and Elizabeth, 1907-1943, 1908, Undated (Box 3b, Folder 4)
    Emily (Mrs. Albert S. Cook, died 1908) and Elizabeth (Mrs. Albert S. Cook, m. 1911, died Dec. 12, 1946)
  - Letters, Mildred Cook and others, 1909, 1933-1959 (Box 3b, Folder 5)
  - Letters, Sidney and Alison Cook, 1907-1944 (Box 3b, Folder 6)
  - Letters, Jacob Cooper to A. S. Cook and E. Sihler, 1888-1902 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Letters, Jacob Cooper, 1881, 1896-1898 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Letters, Jacob Cooper, 1900-1904 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Letter, Andrew D. White to Jacob Cooper, 1898-08-22 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Letters, Mary L. Cooper, 1896-1899 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Letters, Mary L. Cooper, 1900-1904 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Letters, Mary L. Cooper, 1905-1907 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Letters, Mary L. Cooper, 1908-1910 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Letters, Dr. Harry Gold and others, 1946-1959 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Letters, Herbert Gottesman and others, 1939-1949 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Includes an autographed first draft of a letter by Lane Cooper to Gottesman, c.1939
  - Letters, H. J. C. Grierson, 1925-1955 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Letters, Alfred Gudeman, and letters re Gudeman, 1912-1939, 1945-1947 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Letters, Marie Hamilton, 1930-1957 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Letters, Christine Hammer, 1916-1923 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Letters, Marvin Herrick, 1919-1954 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Letters, John Hertz and others, 1932-1959 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Letters, Charles G. Osgood, 1902-12-14-1908-01-10 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Letters, Charles G. Osgood, 1908-01-22-1911-11-15 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Letters, Charles G. Osgood, 1911-11-13-1915-12-28 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Letters, Charles G. Osgood, 1916-04-06-1919-08-30 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Letters, Charles G. Osgood, 1919-10-05-1923-12-11 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Letters, Charles G. Osgood, 1924-01-16-1928-09-18 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    Includes circular letter of the Concordance Society c. Feb. 1928
  - Letters, Charles G. Osgood, 1928-11-19-1935-12-02 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Letters, Charles G. Osgood, 1936-01-13-1944-01-12 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Letters, Charles G. Osgood, 1944-03-20-1959-04-18 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Letters, J. H. Baxter, 1919-1951 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Letters, Madison Bentley, 1912-1940 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Letters, Andrew Bongiorno, 1932-1941 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Letters, Murray W. Bundy, 1919-1926 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Letters, Victor Butterfield, 1927-1959 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Letters, Mr. and Mrs. William W. Comfort, 1900-1956 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Letters, Coolidge O. Chapman, 1923-1956 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Letters, Edgar Dawson, 1901-1943 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Letters, Gertrude Coyne Drake, 1930-1956 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence and other items re making concordances, Undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Pupils and colleagues, Undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
    A. Cutins, Willard Emerson, A. Hooker, Scheetz and others
  - Pupils and colleagues, Undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
    S. Elledge, W. R. Halliday, J. M. Hart, C. H. Hull, Otto Kinkeldey, Wm. Knight, J. F. Mountford, Walter E. Peck, Nowell Smith, Herbert Wichelns
  - Pupils and colleagues, Undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
    M. B. Anderson, M. F. Boynton, Ruby Davis, A. M. Drummond, Mary Ewer, Christine Hammer, Laura Lockwood, Ruth and Dorothy McSparran, Lila Stevenson, Jane M. Urquhart, Helen Pearey Washburn, Marian ('15, cellist)
  - Letters, Ida Langdon, 1905-1956 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Letters, Jacques Maritain, 1953-01-1957-03 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Pupils, colleagues, and other scholars, Undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
    Babbitt, Craigie, Clara Crane, Dowden, J. Wight Duff, E. Gilson, J. H. Hanford, Jespersen, Laistner, Lattley, Legouis, Mountford, Helen North, Pottle, Rhys Roberts, W. D. Ross, Sihler, Spingarn, Wellden, W. K. Wimsatt and others
  - Cornell professors, famous humanists and others, 1902-1954, Undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
    D. D. Eisenhower, van Loon, Cornell Presidents A. D. White, and others; Scholars in English studies in America: Carl Becker, Kittredge, J. L. Lowes, J. M. Manley, Marian Park, Paul Shorey, A. N. Whitehead
  - Letters, Walter MacKellar, 1916-1928 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Letters, Walter MacKellar, 1929-1959 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Letters, Kemp Malone, 1919-1935 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Letters, Donald McGinn, 1930-1955 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Letters, Nath. Micklem, 1928-1956 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Letters, Edna Mount and Frances Dear, 1930-1950 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Letters, New Brunswick (N.J.) and friends of his youth, Undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Letters, Philip Nolan, 1941-1955 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Letters, R. M. Ogden, 1920-1956 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Letters, Frederick M. Padelford, 1899-1940 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Letters, Abbie Findlay Potts, 1918-1924 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Letters, Abbie Findlay Potts, 1924-1955 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Letters, Paul Pritchard, 1925-1956 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Letters, Jules Proctor, 1952-1956 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Letters, E. K. Rand, 1917-1945 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Letters, Burton Rascoe, 1924-1952 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Letters, Robert K. Root, 1899-1926 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Letters, Re Running the Mile, 1896-1897 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Letters, Alice M. Ryan (Sister Mary Anne O.S.B.), 1932-1956 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Letters, Allan Abbott, 1899-1903 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Letters, Joseph Quincy Adams, 1907-1939 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Letters, Joseph Quincy Adams, 1940-1946, Undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Letters, Oliver and Annie Ainsworth, 1917-1928, 1933 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Letters, Marjorie Barstow Greenbie, 1912-1915 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Letters, Marjorie Barstow Greenbie, 1916-1917 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Letters, Marjorie Barstow Greenbie, 1918-1922 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Appointments and recommendations, 1898-1943 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    Includes copies made by Lane Cooper of letters recommending him
  - Letters, Carolyn Whipple (Phillips), 1918-1922 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Letters, Carolyn Whipple (Phillips), 1923-1926, 1929-1935 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Letters, Carolyn Whipple (Phillips), 1937, 1941-1949 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Letters, Carolyn Whipple (Phillips), 1950-1952 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Letters, Carolyn Whipple (Phillips), 1953-1959 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Letters, Charles H. Witman, 1906-1935 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Letters, Burt G. Wilder, A. E. Verrill, G. R. Agassiz, and Simplified Spelling Items, 1907-1917 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Letters, Minoru Yoshida, 1950-1959 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Letters, Charles and Esther Ounn, 1912-1959 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Letters, Frances Foster, 1913-1915 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Letters, Frances Foster, 1916-1923 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Letters, Frances Foster, 1924-1940 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Letters, Lewis Freed, 1939-1957, Undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Letters, Ruth George, 1913-1950 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Letters, Wulker Ratzel, Veghte, Meyer and others, Undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
    In German
  - Letters, Allan H. Gilbert, 1908-1954 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Letters, Edwin J. Howard, 1925-1948 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Letters, J. Howell, 1902-1908 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Letters, Wilbur Samuel Howell, 1925-1959 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Invitations and letters of introduction, Europe, 1900-1904 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Letters, Charles Jones, 1928-1955 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Letters, Putnam Jones, 1926-1940 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Letters, James A. Kleist, S.J., 1932-1946 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Letters, George Lam, 1933-1954 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Letters, Albert W. Liddle, 1919-1932 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Letters, Ralph and Pearle Liddle, 1928-1955 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Student friends in Europe, 1900-1902 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    M. Tilley, S. B. Fay, Francesco Orestano, Gunnar Soderberg
  - Summer Session at Leland Stanford, 1918 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Letters, Bernard Stambler, 1936-1955 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Letters, Theodore Stanton, 1907-1921 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Letters, Frances Noel Stevens, 1900-1909 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Letters, John S. P. Tatlock, 1916-1932 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Letters, Mary Ann Tibbetts Freeman, 1941-1952 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Letters, Chauncey B. Tinker, 1907-1955 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Letters, Mary Rebecca Thayer, 1909-1956 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Letters, George and Dorothy Wertz Tyler, 1928-1958, Undated (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Letters, Carl Van Doren, Max Farrand, and others, 1914-1917 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Letters, William W. B. Van Dyck, 1896-1958 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Letters, John Brownlee Vorhees, 1901-1919 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Letters, William Barnum and others, 1914-1916 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Letter to Melvin Goodwin from Lane Cooper, 1938-01-05 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    Donated by Mr. and Mrs. Arthur Ryan of Ithaca, May 7, 1966
  - Letters, John Marshall and others, 1927-1931 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1909-1957, Undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Letters, Miscellaneous, Undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Acknowledgements upon receipts of his photograph, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Private philanthropy, business, Undated (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence re Shearin's posthumous book on O. E. syntax, 1920-1927 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence re call to Smith College and promotion at Cornell, 1915 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence re Thesaurus Linguae Latinal, 1924 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence re financing of Two Views of Education, 1920-1922 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence re call to University of Michigan, 1927 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Letters, Lane Cooper to Professor Albert S. Cook, 1899 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Letters, Lane Cooper to his father, 1899, Undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Letters, Lane Cooper to his father from Europe, 1899-1900-06 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Letters, Lane Cooper to his father from Europe, 1900-07-1901-03 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Letters, Lane Cooper to his father from Europe, 1901-04-1901-12 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Letters, Lane Cooper to his father and mother, 1902-1904, 1908 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Letters, Lane Cooper to his mother from Europe, 1896-1900-08 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Letters, Lane Cooper to his mother from Europe, 1900-09-1902 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Letters, Lane Cooper to his mother from Europe, 1907-1959 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Letters, Correspondence about farm, 1938, 1949-1955, Undated (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Letter from W. K. Winsatt, Jr., 1946-04-23 (Box 19)
  - Letter from R. M. Ogden, 1935-05-14 (Box 19)
- Assorted Files, 1899-1960
  - Necrology of the Faculty, Cornell University, 1959-1960 (Box 15)
  - Lane Cooper, Undated; Hutton, James (Box 15)
    Reprint from "Yearbook of comparative and General Literature," No.5, Chapel Hill, North Carolina
  - Clippings, Undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Cooper genealogy and biographical notes, Undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Items pertaining to Louis Agassiz, Undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous, Undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Notes by Lane Cooper, Undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Pamphlets, 1915-1960 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Photographs, Undated (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Reprints and printed items, Undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Sheet entitled "Experiments in Education", Undated (Box 19)
  - Ledger, farm accounts to November 1959, 1959-11-29 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Accounts relating to his farm, Undated (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Misc. relating to deaths of Lane Cooper and his father, Undated (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Photographs, Undated (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - "Plato - The Apology", Undated; Kingsley, S. B. (Box 20)
    Student paper
  - "Principles of Literary Criticism", Undated; Caldwell, Elizabeth F. (Box 20)
  - "An Essay in The Art of poetry", Undated; Caldwell, Elizabeth F. (Box 20)
  - "A Translation into Middle English of an Extract from the Symposium of Plato, Taken from Louis Agassiz as a Teacher (pp. 71 - 74) by Professor Lane Cooper", Undated; Kegel, Frank M. (Box 20)
  - "Dante - 2nd Term", Undated; Niles, J. L. (Box 20)
  - "Report on the Early Relations of Coleridge and Wordsworth up to their visit to Germany in 1798", Undated; Baldwin Jr., W. W. (Box 20)
    Student paper; Fld. Also contains: "Sources of Samuel Taylor Coleridge's Ancient Mariner" [no name] and "The Man Coleridge and Nature" Kathleen S. Clark
  - "English Translations of the Greek and Latin Classics", Undated; Work, Silvia (Box 20)
    Student Paper
  - Letter from Florence Callahan, Undated (Box 20)
  - Post card, Undated (Box 20)
  - "Objective study of English", Undated; Hazlett, Effa V. (Box 20)
    Letter and Student Paper
  - "The Teaching of English", Undated; McIsaac R. J. (Box 20)
  - "The study of English", Undated (Box 20)
  - "The Study of English", Undated; Serben, Elizabeth (Box 20)
  - "The Study of English", Undated; Hahn, Mary E. (Box 20)
  - "The Study of English", Undated; Burnett, J. Grace (Box 20)
  - "The Study of English", Undated; Horn, Mary A. (Box 20)
  - "The Study of English", Undated; Cornell, Miss Ethel M. (Box 20)
  - "English in the Public Schools", Undated; Deering, Addie B. (Box 20)
  - "The Study of English", Undated; Harris, Julia (Box 20)
  - "The Teacher of English", Undated; Hall, Jean W. (Box 20)
  - Middle English, Undated; Daley, Joseph M. (Box 20)
  - "Comparative study of Literature 3 Middle English", Undated; Schwartz, Bernard M. (Box 20)
  - "Note Book in Middle English: Comparative study of Literature", Undated; Stewart, Henry P. (Box 20)
  - "My Treasury", Undated; Lowenstein, Lawrence (Box 20)
    Notebook; student paper
  - "The Artistic Ordering of Life", Undated; Lowenstein, Lawrence (Box 20)
  - "Popular Enthusiasm Over Cathedral Building in the Twelfth Century", Undated (Box 20)
    Printed pamphlet; student paper
  - Manuscripts, notes, and correspondence regarding cooper's publications; drafts of his reviews of others' writings, Undated (Box 21)
  - Manuscripts, notes, and correspondence regarding cooper's publications; drafts of his reviews of others' writings, Undated (Box 22)
  - Manuscripts, notes, and correspondence regarding cooper's publications; drafts of his reviews of others' writings, Undated (Box 23)
  - Milton's "Sampson Agonistes", Undated (Box 24)
    Manuscript of Lane Cooper; reprint
  - "Othello", Undated (Box 24)
  - Wordsworth's Druids, Undated (Box 24)
    Manuscript of Lane Cooper; notes
  - "The Death of Wallenstein", Undated (Box 24)
  - Christopher Marlow's "Dr. Faustus", Undated (Box 24)
  - Brome play "Abraham & Isaac", Undated (Box 24)
    Manuscript of Lane Cooper; manuscript
  - Browning "Prometheus Bound", Undated (Box 24)
  - Jebb translation, The Tragedies of Sophocles, "Oedipus the King", Undated (Box 24)
  - Letter from Albert s. Cook with his notes on the Owl, Undated (Box 24)
    Manuscript of Lane Cooper
  - Envelope with " __ Metallic Door Co.,", Undated (Box 24)
    Contains miscellaneous items - notes, newspaper clippings, ship brochure, etc.
  - Talk on Agassiz before Agassiz Club of Cornell, Monday evening, 1917-12-03 (Box 24)
    Zoological Lecture Room
  - "Daffodil Fields", Undated (Box 24)
    Contains notes and letters concerning Albert S. Cook's research into Icelandic sagas
  - "The Sun as King: Shakespeare and the Ancients", Undated (Box 24)
    Notes
  - "Allegory", Undated (Box 24)
    Notes on the topic
  - "Pascua Florides", Undated (Box 24)
    Single note
  - Notes for articles, Undated (Box 24)
  - "Dante to Polycletus", Undated (Box 24)
  - "Fortune's Wheel", Undated (Box 24)
  - "Settles Pamphlets", Undated (Box 24)
    Manuscript
  - "Review of Collins' Tennyson", Undated (Box 24)
  - Latin notes from seneca, Cicero, and others, Undated (Box 24)
  - Theses subjects, Undated (Box 24)
  - Poetry notes, Undated (Box 24)
  - Remarks for Princeton, 1923 (Box 24)
    Speech notes for opening of a formal discussion at the annual meeting of the American Philological Association, Princeton
  - Scattered Notes Designed for MLN, Undated (Box 24)
  - Plato, Phaedo, Undated (Box 24)
  - "Caesar's Marches", Undated (Box 24)
  - "Friend to Friend", Undated (Box 24)
  - "Lycidas 130", Undated; Chauncey, Edward and Baldwin (Box 24)
    Article; notes
  - "Material for Brief Notes", Undated (Box 24)
  - "Dew from Moon", Undated (Box 24)
    References in literature
  - "Milton's Atlantic stone", Undated (Box 24)
    Notes and references
  - "Montjore", Undated (Box 24)
  - "Collectives with Adjectives descriptive of individuals", Undated (Box 24)
    References
  - "Fleecy star", Undated (Box 24)
  - "Macbeth 1.3.7 'Tiger'", Undated (Box 24)
  - "Pictures on Walls", Undated (Box 24)
  - "Oenone", Undated (Box 24)
  - "Publicans", Undated (Box 24)
  - "Bossuet", Undated (Box 24)
    Manuscript on note cards
  - "Talk on Poetics of Aristotle - Chicago Classical Club, 1922", 1922 (Box 24)
    Note cards
  - "Life is Life", Undated (Box 24)
    Notes and references on phrase form Ita is a" letter from Mrs. Elizabeth Stambler re poetry references
  - "On the Sources of Kubla Khan", Undated (Box 24)
  - "Adonais", Undated (Box 24)
  - "Speech at Rutgers celebrations 1916", Undated (Box 24)
    Notes and Rutgers' President's letter to Cooper
  - "Letter to President Day, Jan. 1, 1942", 1942-01-01 (Box 24)
  - "Easty Lives on Milton's Wives", Undated (Box 24)
  - "Coleridge's 'Brother' in Wordsworth's Castle of Indolence", Undated (Box 24)
    Article
  - "What is a Poet?", 1899 (Box 24)
    Manuscript of master's degree speech given at Rutgers
  - "8 Division of Writings" and "9 Col. etc.", Undated (Box 24)
    Lectures
  - Unpublished - notes, Undated; Cook, A. S. (Box 24)
    A. S. Cook's notes and references on Bees
  - Thomas De Quincy, Undated (Box 24)
  - Lord Byron as a Satirist, Undated (Box 24)
  - Landor Lecture I & II, Undated (Box 24)
  - Good Usage, Undated (Box 24)
  - Wordsworth's Concept of the Ancient Mariner, Undated (Box 24)
  - The Complete Poetical Works of William Wordsworth - review, Undated (Box 24)
  - Bees Copy, Undated (Box 24)
  - Bees, Undated (Box 24)
  - Cooper Bibliography, Undated (Box 24)
  - "Old Books and New in Education", Undated (Box 24)
    Speech
  - Life of Coleridge, Undated (Box 24)
  - "Forest Hermit" in Coleridge and Wordsworth, Undated (Box 24)
  - Review of La Vie d'un Poete: Coleridge, Undated (Box 24)
  - Hymns Old and New, Undated (Box 24)
  - Greek criticism of Greek Drama, Undated (Box 24)
  - "The Treatment of Intellectual Pride in Literature", Undated (Box 24)
  - From Opinions on Teaching by Means of Lecture, Undated (Box 24)
  - The Teaching of English and the study of the Classics, Undated (Box 24)
  - The College of Arts and Sciences, Undated (Box 24)
  - Miscellaneous, Undated (Box 24)
  - Additional Material (Box 25)